{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"3821","name":"Shabazz East Restaurant","address":"4712-16 Cadillac Blvd","zipcode":"48214","owner":"Hosea Hollins","licenseNumber":"063690","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":null,"reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","coords":"-82.99508,42.37990","geojson":{"id":"3821","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-82.995076763,42.379896081]},"properties":{"name":"Shabazz East Restaurant","owner":"Hosea Hollins","address":"4712-16 Cadillac Blvd","zipcode":"48214","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":null,"license_number":"063690","establishmentid":"3821","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"180.0","most_recent_license_date":"4/8/2019"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"1037","name":"Detroit Lions Academy","address":"10101 E Canfield","zipcode":"48214"},{"establishmentid":"4999","name":"Big A's Concessions","address":"5119 Cadillac St","zipcode":"48213"},{"establishmentid":"3324","name":"Timbuktu Academy","address":"10800 E Canfield Rd","zipcode":"48214"},{"establishmentid":"1392","name":"Williams and Sons Ice Cream","address":"10700 Mack Ave","zipcode":"48214"},{"establishmentid":"1244","name":"Bethel Baptist Church East","address":"5715 Holcomb St","zipcode":"48213"},{"establishmentid":"1158","name":"Franklin Gourmet Dairy Bar","address":"8405 Mack Ave","zipcode":"48214"},{"establishmentid":"1737","name":"Genesis House III (EAST)","address":"3840 Fairview St","zipcode":"48214"},{"establishmentid":"1436","name":"Blackwell Institute","address":"9330 Shoemaker St","zipcode":"48213"},{"establishmentid":"3555","name":"Friends of Detroit & Tri County","address":"8230 E Forest Ave","zipcode":"48214"},{"establishmentid":"4831","name":"Cesar Chavez Academy - East","address":"4130 Maxwell","zipcode":"48214"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"43899","inspectionDate":"2018-10-24T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"On the Floor","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"Under the Counter(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Routine inspections","subItem":"of premises for evidence of pests","problemDescription":"Not performed","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"Under the Counter(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Inspections must be performed as stated above."}]},{"inspectionid":"41956","inspectionDate":"2018-04-17T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Routine inspections","subItem":"of premises for evidence of pests","problemDescription":"Not performed","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"Along the Wall (South)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Inspections must be performed as stated above."}]},{"inspectionid":"40624","inspectionDate":"2017-10-31T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"6-202.15","violationDescription":"Outer openings of a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT shall be protected against the entry of insects and rodents. Unless otherwise allowed by law. \r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Outer opening(s)","subItem":"door(s)","problemDescription":"Not tight-fitting","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"At the base of the Door","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair/replace to meet requirements above."},{"violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Routine inspections","subItem":"of premises for evidence of pests","problemDescription":"Not performed","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"On top of the Cans","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Inspections must be performed as stated above."}]},{"inspectionid":"38513","inspectionDate":"2017-04-19T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\r\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\r\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Missing","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"At the PERSON IN CHARGE","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."}]},{"inspectionid":"36814","inspectionDate":"2016-10-13T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Inside the Stove","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"4-602.12","violationDescription":"(A) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking and baking EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours. This section does not apply to hot oil cooking and filtering EQUIPMENT if it is cleaned as specified in Subparagraph 4-602.11(D)(6).   \r\n(B) The cavities and door seals of microwave ovens shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours by using the manufacturer's recommended cleaning procedure.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Microwave oven door seals and cavities","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"Through out the day as necessary","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Inside the Microwave Oven(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"On the bottom of Spices","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\r\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\r\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Drainage system","subItem":"drain lines","problemDescription":"Not constructed, designed, installed according to law","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Under the Handsink","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove and replace to be in compliance with law."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"At the Floor","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2019-03-31T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"3821"}}